Time to atone for your sin, Prince Marse.
彌補自己犯下的錯吧 馬爾斯王子
Do so, and you shall have His Majesty's forgiveness
這樣就能得到皇帝的原諒
and win back the princess you love.
還能得到心愛的公主
Who are you?
妳是什麼人
A spy from the empire?
果然是帝國的間諜嗎
I am just a normal seer.
我只是平凡的占卜師
I can see your future
能看到你的未來
thanks to my divination.
全都是拜占卜所賜
However,
只不過
my divination is usually very accurate.
我的占卜很準
The last monster attack was a good example.
就好比上次魔物的來襲
The Ring King is an outsider from a different world.
那位戒王是來自外界的異物
He is not meant to linger in this world.
不是適合待在這個世界的人
You were the one worthy of becoming the Ring King.
你原本就擁有當戒王的資格
I don't see why you should be concerned.
根本沒什麼好介意的
Or perhaps
還是說
you wish to go against His Majesty's will?
你又想違背皇帝的旨意
This sword is capable of altering the flow of mana.
這是能扭曲魔素流動的劍
It's an ancient weapon
在傳說中曾經被讚譽過的
sung in legends and tales.
古代魔道具
Now, you will carry it.
這把劍就送給你吧
Despite not having any special abilities,
就算是沒有任何力量的你
you can defeat the Ring King with this sword.
只要有了這個就不會輸給戒王了
Where did you get this?
妳怎麼會有這種東西
I certainly hope you bring the rings back home.
希望你能帶著戒指回到帝國
I'll be waiting.
我會等著你
TALES OF WEDDING RINGS
《婚戒物語》
What is wrong with me?
我是怎麼了
After all the effort I've put into you, you can't even handle a border country?
我為你準備了那麼多 你卻連一個邊境國家都搞不定
Do you know what the officials think of you?
你知道大臣們都怎麼稱呼你嗎
They see you as a living failure!
他們稱你是廢物
A new Ring King will be selected soon.
近期要選擇成為戒王的人
It's an old wives' tale,
雖然那只是老掉牙的傳說
but it serves as a great way to earn the people's trust.
卻是贏得民心的好話題
I trust you won't
這種程度的小事
fail a task as simple as this.
你應該不至於搞砸吧
You are only valuable because you're my son.
身為我的兒子就是你的價值
That's all there is to it.
僅此而已
Show me your worth,
展現你的價值吧
Marmarugias.
馬爾瑪利基亞斯
I've really lost everything.
我真的失去一切了呢
What should I do?
我該怎麼辦
That's right.
沒錯
This is the only path to take.
我只剩這條路可走了
We are launching a campaign against the monster.
我們接下來要去討伐魔物
Are you sure I should stay?
我真的不用去嗎
The campaign is not your responsibility.
這不是你的職責
When a single unit gets too powerful,
一個人的力量太強
the pacing of the entire army will be disrupted.
會打亂全體的步調
You exist as a last resort
像你這樣的人
when push comes to shove.
是為了以防萬一而存在的
Take care of this place.
這裡就拜託你了
Yes.
好
Satou!
佐藤
Well... You know...
那個 就是…呃…
What is it?
什麼
Whatever!
真是的
If you have to go into battle,
要是你臨時非得去戰鬥
at least you'll be ready.
那就麻煩了
Thanks.
謝謝妳
Don't be so bashful. It's embarrassing.
別害羞啦 好丟臉
Well, I'm still not used to this.
沒有啦 我只是還不習慣
Allow me to lend you my strength as well!
我也助你一臂之力吧
Hold on! Granart!
等等 葛蘭納托
What?
幹嘛
I'm his wife too.
我也是佐藤的老婆喔
Is it wrong for us to kiss?
這麼做有什麼問題嗎
No! But that doesn't mean...
沒有 雖然沒有…
Excuse me.
那個
Can I...
既然這樣 我也…
Not you too, Nephrites!
連涅芙麗緹絲也來
Is that a no?
不行嗎
Well, I'm not saying you can't...
不 也不是不行
Well...
那就…
Nephrites is actually so enthused for once.
涅芙麗緹絲居然那麼積極
All right, I get to do it again!
那就我一個人再多做一次吧
That's cheating, Princess Krystal!
克莉絲朵殿下好奸詐
What is going on here?
那是怎樣啊
This is ridiculous beyond any words.
我已經傻眼到說不出話來
The bond with the Ring King serves as the power source.
與戒王之間的情意就是力量
They are willing to share their power to the Ring King.
既然她們自願給戒王力量
Isn't that a good thing?
那不是很好嗎
For real?
是這樣嗎
Report!
報告
We are advancing smoothly on the right and left flanks.
右翼和左翼的戰線都順利推進中
Is that so?
是嗎
The monster army is somehow acting the way our seer predicted.
魔物大軍很奇妙地 與占卜師的預言如出一轍
At this rate,
但是按照這個發展
victory will be ours for sure.
我軍可以說是勝券在握
Prince Sluder!
斯琉達大人
A giant monster
有一隻巨大的魔物
showed up at the most unexpected location.
出現在意想不到的地方
It will breach Maasa palace soon.
這樣下去 牠將會闖進麻薩王宮
Please dispatch a troop to the palace.
請馬上分出一支部隊前往王宮吧
No. We will defend this place.
不 我們就死守在這裡
The palace will do fine without us.
王宮不會有事的
What's going on?
怎麼了
Hurry!
快點
Into the palace!
進王宮
A monster!
魔物
It seems there's only one.
看起來好像只有一隻
Satou!
佐藤
Mr. Marse!
馬爾斯先生
Ring King.
戒王
I feel bad about this, but you must die now!
不好意思 我要請你死在這裡
Oh no!
不妙
I'll take care of the monster.
魔物交給我
Satou, deal with Marse.
佐藤你對付馬爾斯
Mr. Marse.
馬爾斯先生
What's going on?
你怎麼了
Kill the Ring King
殺死戒王
and bring the rings home.
把戒指帶回帝國
Such is my mission as the empire's prince.
這是我身為帝國皇子的使命
At this point,
我現在…
it's the only thing I can do!
只剩下這條路可走了
Wait!
等一下
You must have a good reason to do this.
一定有什麼原因吧
Tell me about it!
告訴我理由
You said so yourself.
是你自己說的吧
If it's important,
如果有重要的理由
we should just take it!
只要搶走就行了
I became your guide
幫你們帶路
and earned your trust
贏取你們的信任
for this very moment.
都是為了這一刻
For the sake of the empire,
為了帝國
you must fall!
我要打倒你
Satou!
佐藤
Marse is not acting like himself.
馬爾斯他不太正常
I fear he's being manipulated.
恐怕是被操控了
What should I do now?
那我該怎麼辦
Will holy water turn him back to normal?
拿聖水潑他就能恢復嗎
How should I know?
我不知道
That being said,
雖然不知道
you must stop him.
總之你先阻止他的行動
Gramps! Why do you always get so useless when I need you?
爺爺你還是老樣子 在緊要關頭總是派不上用場
There's no way I can defeat him with just my sword.
憑我的劍術根本不可能贏過他
In that case...
既然這樣…
How is this happening?
這是怎麼回事
Amusing.
真有趣
A sword that alters the flow of mana.
能扭曲魔素的劍嗎
He's holding a nostalgic weapon.
他拿著令人懷念的東西
Who would've thought that piece of trash could wield this sword?
沒想到那種廢物 居然會拿出那把劍
However,
不過
it suits that worthless young man very well.
跟那位沒用的年輕人滿相配的
I knew it.
果然沒錯
The ring is talking to me.
是戒指在跟我說話
No need to hesitate.
不需要猶豫
With the power of the rings, you can come out on top.
只要用戒指的魔力就能贏過他
Turn him into a pile of ashes.
讓他灰飛煙滅吧
I can never do that!
這種事我哪做得到
Would you rather get killed?
難道你想被殺嗎
Shut it! You talk too much!
吵死了 閉嘴
I told you, I can't do it!
我說做不到就是做不到
Why would you hesitate to defeat a foe with your own power?
用自己的力量排除障礙 有什麼好猶豫的
What a fool.
真蠢
That's true enough, but how do I pull it off?
話是這麼說 但我該怎麼辦
If I use my full power,
要是使出全力
I could perish him like the ring said.
也許就會變得跟戒指說的一樣
But Marse isn't an opponent I can win by pulling punches.
但他又不是放水也打得贏的對手
Yeah. I've never defeated him.
對啊 我根本打不贏他
So,
可是
why am I still unscathed?
為什麼我到現在都毫髮無傷
I knew it.
果然
Mr. Marse never changes.
馬爾斯先生就是馬爾斯先生
Satou is fighting Mr. Marse?
佐藤在跟馬爾斯先生戰鬥
Why?
為什麼
No idea.
我也不知道
Marse wants to steal the rings.
馬爾斯說他要搶走戒指
That fool! He's going to get himself killed!
笨蛋 他想死嗎
I knew it.
果然沒錯
You couldn't bring yourself to kill me.
你很猶豫要不要砍我吧
That's because you have a kind heart.
因為你是個善良的人
Kill me, Satou.
殺了我吧 佐藤
I was abandoned by my lover.
我是被心愛的人放棄
I'm a failure who can fulfil my duty as a prince.
也無法達成帝國皇子使命的廢物
I even hurt you.
甚至 還砍傷了你
I am utterly worthless now.
我已經沒有任何價值
I quite like you, Mr. Marse.
我很喜歡你喔
Honestly, without you,
老實說 要不是有你
I would've died by now.
我在來到這裡的時候就沒命了
I've made it this far
是你的善良救了我
because your kindness saved me.
我才能走到現在
If you think yourself worthless,
如果你說自己沒價值
I'll make you priceless.
那就讓我成為你的價值
You're the comrade of a legendary hero who will save the world.
與傳說中的戒王 一起拯救世界的夥伴
Nothing can be more valuable than that.
沒有比這更有價值的事了吧
I need you.
我需要你
You want me to become...
你要成為我的…
Crush the gem at the hilt.
打碎劍柄的寶石
Every one of them
每個人都一樣
is just as worthless.
完全派不上用場
My magic won't hold for long!
魔法撐不住了
Oh no!
糟了
Hime!
小姬
Saphira!
瑟菲菈
Is it taking her hostage?
是想拿她當人質嗎
You ruined the gift I sent you,
難得我送你禮物 卻被你糟蹋了
Prince Marse.
馬爾斯皇子
I knew it. You are with the monsters.
妳和魔物果然是同夥
It was you who cursed the sword.
在劍上下詛咒的人就是妳吧
Divination isn't an impressive art.
雖說是占卜 但也沒什麼了不起
I merely unshackled the heart
只是解開內心的枷鎖
and made his desire burn stronger.
讓願望稍微變強烈而已
You know that very well, Prince Marse.
你應該很清楚吧 馬爾斯王子
No sudden movement
要是敢輕舉妄動
or Princess Saphira will die.
瑟菲菈公主就沒命了
Well? Will you trade the rings for her life?
怎麼樣 要不要拿戒指來交換
You're right.
的確
I envy Satou.
我羨慕佐藤
I even thought about taking his life.
甚至想奪走他的性命
However,
但是
that's not all of me.
那並不是我的全部
Satou risked his life to make me realise that.
是佐藤奮不顧身告訴我這一點
Mr. Marse.
馬爾斯先生…
I won't hesitate any more.
我不會再猶豫了
I will live for myself
我決定要為自己
and for those I cherish.
還有重視的人而活
I'll walk my own path.
我要走自己選擇的道路
That's my worth.
這就是我的價值
Princess Saphira!
瑟菲菈公主
Please marry me!
請妳嫁給我吧
Have you lost your mind?
你在說什麼蠢話
Eat this!
看招
It's cheating to say that now,
在這種時候說太狡猾了
Prince Marse.
馬爾斯殿下
Sorry for the wait.
對不起 讓妳等這麼久
Curse you!
混蛋 混蛋
I was hoping to have fun with you
我本來想在王完全醒來前
before the King fully awakens.
陪你們玩玩的
But I'm tired of playing by your rules!
但我不想再配合你們世界的規矩了
Return to the abyss!
給我回歸深淵吧
What is this thing?
這是什麼啊
She finally shows her true nature.
終於露出真面目了嗎
Unbelievable.
真是的
You really are a fool
你果然是個傻瓜
who's kind to a fault.
也太濫好人了
But you're a nice fool.
不過是個還不錯的傻瓜
What...
什…
The power of this ring commands the source of life.
操控生命源頭的水戒之力
Witness the true power of the Dragonkin!
好好見識龍人的真正力量吧
She devoured the monster!
居然吃了
She slipped away.
逃掉了啊
Incredible.
好厲害
Can you still turn back to normal?
這變得回來嗎
Of course.
當然可以
Don't look.
不可以看
Satou.
佐藤
Sorry,
不好意思
let's finish what we started.
能不能繼續剛剛沒做完的事
Thank you for saving Maasa.
謝謝你救了我國麻薩
Who is that dude?
誰啊
My father.
是我父皇
Huh!?
什麼
I was bewitched by the Abyss King's knight,
雖然之前被深淵王的騎士 蒙蔽了心智
but I haven't missed a thing.
但朕全都看在眼裡
The Ring King and his legendary power
戒王 傳說的力量
are all real.
看來都是真的
As a Ring Kingdom,
身為戒之國的國民
Maasa will provide you with full support.
麻薩也會盡全力協助你的
Thank you so much!
謝…謝謝
Heroes from the empire,
還有帝國的各位
thank you for defending Maasa.
謝謝你們保護了麻薩
But from now on,
不過以後
the Kingdom of Water will defend itself.
我們會靠自己的力量保護水之國
I was too stubborn and believed I had to protect the kingdom myself.
因為朕太執著 認為必須自己保護麻薩
I let it fall into the villain's hand.
才會讓它落入奸賊的手中
But with an ally as powerful as the empire,
但現在知道有帝國這個強大的盟友
I won't make the same mistake.
就不會再重蹈覆轍
That's wonderful.
那真是太好了
We will rush to your aid should the need arise.
如果需要幫忙 我們會再次趕來
Summon us with your will.
請以王的旨意召喚我們
You went through a lot,
讓妳吃苦了
Saphir.
瑟菲珞
It seems she also has a candid side, huh?
看來她也有坦率的一面嘛
You managed to find yourself a great husband.
而且妳好像也找到一位好丈夫了
Huh?
什麼
He is just a fool with magic power.
這種東西 只是擁有魔力的傻瓜
You're still as bad at judging characters.
看來父皇的眼光還是很爛呢
Is... Is that so?
是…是這樣嗎
Water King.
水之王
As the Ring King's knight, Marmarugias,
我想以戒王的騎士 馬爾瑪利基亞斯的身分
I have a request to make.
拜託您一件事
Allow me to marry Princess Saphira.
請讓我迎娶瑟菲菈公主為妻
Prince Marse...
馬爾斯皇子…
No, I should call you Knight Marse now.
不 現在應該叫你馬爾斯騎士
From the day you left
從你離開後
until Saphir made me come to my senses,
到瑟菲珞讓朕醒悟之前
I had never paid attention to Saphira's feelings.
朕完全沒注意到瑟菲菈的心意
I cared too much about the nation, and my daughters suffered for it.
因為太在乎國家 害心愛的女兒受苦
I've failed as their father.
真是個失敗的父親
I leave her in your capable hands.
朕的女兒就交給你了
Yes!
是
Princess Saphira.
瑟菲菈公主
Prince Marse.
馬爾斯殿下
That's great.
那個樣子 真好
I want to be like them.
我也想變得像他們一樣
Satou.
佐藤
I got ahead of you.
我搶先了
What does that mean?
"搶先"是什麼意思
We got married first...
結婚的話 明明是我們先…
Could it be...
難道說
They've done it!
他們已經做過了嗎
Brother.
皇兄
That seer and her monsters
那個占卜師和魔物
and their connection with the empire...
以及他們與帝國之間的關係
A conspiracy is brewing
在我看不到的地方
where I can't see.
似乎有什麼陰謀正在進行
I must return to the capital at once.
我得盡快趕回帝都
You must come home someday.
總有一天 你一定要回來
I'll be waiting.
我等你
Yes.
好
You failed to take Maasa.
妳好像沒有拿下麻薩
It was under the empire's control for a while.
雖然一度讓它受到帝國掌控
But that cursed girl...
結果被那個臭丫頭…
However, a puny nation like that
不過那種國家
means nothing to Your Majesty.
對皇帝陛下根本不足掛齒吧
As long as I still command the monsters
只要能操控魔物的我
and we work together,
和皇帝你攜手合作
we can conquer more kingdoms.
就能拿下更多的國家
Yes. You can accomplish that.
沒錯 你能做到這一點
Show me your desire.
讓我看看你的欲望
You'd come after me now that Maasa is useless to you?
麻薩王沒用了就盯上我嗎
I only listened to you because our interests align.
因為利害關係一致 我才會聽妳的話
It seems the obsolete can't be trusted after all.
老舊的東西果然還是不行啊
Darn you!
你這傢伙
You knew it all along!
一開始就全都知道了嗎
We don't live in the age of gods. It's the age of men!
現在不是神的時代 是人的時代
I will eradicate anyone who stands in my way.
礙事者必須通通剷除
Whether it's the Abyss King
不管對象是深淵王
or the Ring King.
還是戒王都一樣